

Viola Josephine Hestbech

I'm Viola, a 22-year old, born and raised in Copenhagen, and daughter to a psychologist mom and a yoga teacher dad. It's been a ride.

I currently live right on the border between Østerbro and Nørrebro, which is lovely, because downtown Nørrebro is where I'm studying Multimedia Design in the international class, going on third semester. In my free time, I love to watch DR series or comedy shows and read books and articles about youth and humans and stuff, though I spent most of my time either working or going to school. I'm a bit of a "save the turtles"-nut, through I also disagree very strongly with the performance culture/ perfectionistic tendencies that are on the rise in our society, so I'd like to think that I'm not a fanatic. I practise figure skating twice a week and then I try to go driving every now and again, because I just got my drivers license. Hardest thing ever!

In a few years, I'll probably be cruising southern Europe in a campervan, or studying sociology/psychology somewhere in Denmark[©]

After high school, I decided to pack my bag and go to Australia, India and Indonesia for 8 months to work and travel, which was an incredible experience. After that, I worked fulltime as a floor manager at a coffee shop in the airport for about a year, going to work hours before the sun rose, which I did until I started studying Multimedia Design, as mentioned above. My education has given me tools, that now allows me to create websites for several of my mother's psychologist colleagues, on the side of my studies and my other job. I also write and create content for my own pleasure that I sometimes share on my website or on my Instagram.

As a part of a work team, I am happy, eager and when I work with topics that interest me, I am very passionate and rich in ideas. I often think outside the box, which sometimes feels like an insecurity to me, but it's also lead me to many solutions that were interesting and different in a good way.

Klostervænget 4, 3, -433 2100 København Ø (+45) 60 55 24 17 violaviolaviola1@gmail.com

COMPETENCEES

- Basic coding in HTML, CSS & JavaScript
- Comfortable working in most Adobe programmes (Photoshop, Illustrator, Premiere Pro, etc)
- Have worked heaps with concept development and visual identities
- Have experience with user research and implementing data
- Experience writing SoMe cations and doing mockups, as well as working with Facebook Business Manager
- Work efficiently in groups/teams

See more on portfolio site... 3

LANGUAGES

Danish – Mother tongue

English – Fluent

Indonesian − A bit[©]

EDUCATION

KEA (Copenhagen School of Design and Technology), Copenhagen,

Denmark – AP in Multimedia Design Int.

August 2020 - June 2022

I'm currently studying Multimedia Design at Copenhagen School of Design and Technology. I'm learning how to create digital solutions, with a focus on graphical- and web design, as well as content creations for digital medias. Furthermore, on our third semester, I have selected to specify the direction of the course, by picking the Digital Design and Content elective. This elective focuses on journalism, content, storytelling, qualitative research, web features, as well as marketing and e-commerce.

Niels Brock IBB, Copenhagen, Denmark – International Business

Baccalaureate

August 2015 - June 2018

In Copenhagen, I went to Copenhagen Business College. There, we had a specific focus on business, however, I also graduated courses, such as, psychology and market communication, et cetera. The school has a focus on internationality and I studied and graduated all courses in English. Every year, we had an exchange stay to another country.

Algonquin College, Ottawa, Canada – *Exchange stay*

January 2017 - March 2017

The second time I was an exchange student I went to Canada for two months. This was a cold experience that again helped me expand my English vocabulary. This time I got to see a lot of the country, including the obligatory ice hockey match.

Santa Ynez Union High School, California, USA – Exchange stay

August 2015 - December 2015

During college in Copenhagen I was an exchange student twice. The first time, I went to California for four months, where I went to a typical American high school. Even though we lived with host families, the experience contributed to my sense of responsibility, as well as my ability to speak English fluently.

WORK EXPERIENCE

The Organic Boho, Christianshavn, Denmark – Waitress/barista

June 20120 - October 2020

I started working for the Organic Boho, because I liked some of the things they promoted, such as a plant based, organic and sustainable menu. I had a great time there, but was unfortunately let go when the company closed its doors at the end of last year. The

experience did, however, develop my waitress- and barista skills further, as well as keep my English language practiced, with most of both employees and customers being international.

Lagkagehuset, Copenhagen Airport, Denmark – *Floor manager/ Barista*

March 2019 - Present

As a floor manager in one of Denmark's busiest Lagkagehuset shops, I am responsible for the daily overview and for a well-functioning store when I am the leader in charge. I very much adore the international environment and the social encounters that is a big part of my job in the airport. Out there, I am given the chance to further develop my coffee skills, by attending coffee courses and making hundreds of lattes and flat whites for the thirsty passengers of Copenhagen airport. I am also often asked to come in when the store manager can see that an employee with strong coffee skills is needed for a shift.

Due to the unusual working hours at the airport, I am given the opportunity to prove my punctuality and my commitment. Working there, has given also me the ability to handle and stay calm through hour-long rushes of customers.

Smart Energy Group, Byron Bay, Australia-Salesperson

August 2018 - December 2018

My job as a telemarketer included informing and negotiating with houseowners in Northeastern Australia, that an energy expert come to their house and look at potential opportunities for installation of solar panels on their property, so they could save money on their electricity bill, long term. As a salesperson, I learned different sales techniques, as well as further development of my English language and -pronunciation, and a solid Australian accent, when needed I learned that people buy from people that they like and that it can be beneficial to grab their hand and guide them rather than push a product onto them. It was important for me that I supported a sustainable product, and thus I had a great time with the company, but unfortunately had to leave to celebrate New Years/Christmas in India and Bali with friends and family. I was offered a job, should I ever come back to Byron.

Espresso house, Valby, Denmark – *Barista/"aspirant"*

February 2015 - January 2018

From I was 15 to 18, I worked for the largest coffee chain in Scandinavia, formerly known as Baresso. As an "aspirant" (below 18yo), I learned the basics of selling coffee and food, handling customers, using the cashier, and general cleaning. When I turned 18, I was trained as a barista, and learned to steam and make coffee, according to their standards. I was also trained in counting the cash at the end of the day, and being in charge when I had shifts, as well as having the general overview and responsibility when I was there. The feedback from colleagues and customers was overall positive and I was Employee Of The Month several times.